<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>annowiki.blog</title>
    <description>The blog for anno.wiki</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 14:35:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 14:35:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Populating the Database</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;So reddit might&lt;/span&gt;  just be the place to find some users. I have
one interested person that came out of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/shakespeare/comments/cuiw6s/i_devoted_my_last_year_to_building_something_for/&quot;&gt;r/shakespeare&lt;/a&gt; post. It is hard
for me to expect people to annotate if I don’t, so I’ve been annotating myself
somewhat. I’ve added about 20. I want to add more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added a new tag, speculation, for when an annotation is warranted but there is
no proof for the assertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve said time and time again, I do not know where users will want to go with
the way the culture operates &lt;em&gt;because I have no users yet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning on posting to r/books tomorrow. They expect you to have previous
interaction with the community. So I went on a posting spree and now I’m up to
312 points pretty much just from r/books. It was surprisingly easy. They are
friendly folks. This also means that when my first month is up on Reddit I’ll be
able to create an annowiki subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also am planning on posting to Show HN tomorrow on Hacker News. We’ll see if
it gets upvoted. I’ll try again if it doesn’t. It sounds like HN Hug of Death is
nowhere near as severe as I anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems my Google SEO is not so bad. If you search for “Hamlet anno”, for
instance, you’ll get me as the third result. “anno wiki” still puts me on the
second page, but hopefully that will change. Don’t know how to do a sitemap, but
will figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’m going to start adding some books. This is a list of stuff I’m
interested in adding in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geneva Bible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book of Common Prayer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plautus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ovid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chaucer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Homer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pope&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joyce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dickens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keats, Byron, Shelley, Wordsworth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jane Austen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Milton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Song of Roland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eugene O’Neill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tennessee Williams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whitman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mellville&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fredrick Douglass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncle Tom’s Cabin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beowulf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Henry James&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jonathan Edwards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balzac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zola&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JS Mill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proudhon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bakunin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it for now.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 04:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/19/population</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/19/population</guid>
        
        
        <category>annowiki</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Launch in Earnest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;Been a while.&lt;/span&gt;  Sorry about that. Wanted a break after a year
of anno.wiki. Decided learning French would be the route. Still learning. I’m
reading Harry Potter et le Prisonnier d’Azkaban. But I wanted to get back to
this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened up registration. I decided I don’t have enough friends for a beta, and
it seems that random strangers are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; actually interested in beta testing
some random dude’s app. Even if it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; totally awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m trying to find people interested in annotating. This app won’t be
useful until there are annotators. Whenever I’ve explained the concept to
people, they’ve always wondered if there would be people interested in reading
the annotations. I have always said I’m not worried at all about lurkers or
readers, I’m worried about writers. Are there enough people as crazy as me to
want to annotate classic literature? Judging by the number of annotated editions
of literature in existence, I would bet yes. But they were paid, and I don’t
have money. So this is still a worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listened to a talk by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Wales&quot;&gt;Jimmy Wales&lt;/a&gt; once where he described expecting
nothing from Wikipedia, that it would be DOA when it was born, and then being
shocked by hundreds of articles when he looked at it a couple weeks later. The
Internet was quite different in 2001. There were Usenet boards and BBS’s where
someone making something interesting could go and show it to people who would be
interested in joining. Now everyone’s siloed in Facebook, Reddit, or Twitter,
and the idea that you can just post in a Reddit like r/literature is a joke. I
messaged the mods, they thanked me for messaging before posting and then told
me, kindly, to get lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/shakespeare/comments/cuiw6s/i_devoted_my_last_year_to_building_something_for/&quot;&gt;r/shakespeare&lt;/a&gt;, but that didn’t go very far. Thank you for the
praise, all you kindly r/shakespeare readers, but nobody seemed interested
enough to contribute. I’ve though that, perhaps, in my fear of being perceived
as a promoter (which I am), I would have the thread deleted, so I focused on my
story and made it only incidentally about anno.wiki. The result is a little
wordy. Let’s not kid ourselves, it’s a wall of text. I’ll post there again in a
month and make it more blatantly promotional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emailed Jimmy Wales and Wikimedia. They pointed me to the Village Pump, where
I &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Village_pump_(miscellaneous)#Advice_for_new_wiki_project_for_literature,_not_affiliated_with_Wikipedia&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; yesterday asking for advice. No luck so far. That &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; take a
couple of days. In all likelihood, though, no one will respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emailed an old college buddy of mine. We’ll see how far that gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two next possibilities, that I’m holding off on because they seem drastic,
are to, (1), email every professor from here to the West Coast (and in the UK as
well) who might be interested in classical literature, and (2), post to Hacker
News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don’t like those options. The first because I don’t like being a spamming
whore. The second because I don’t want an HN Hug of Death from a community that
might only be somewhat interested in literature, and from which maybe only one
in every millionth hit will be someone interested in contributing. The result
would be expensive with little payoff, in my mind. Plus I don’t have an account
with rep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I’m starting to get a little discouraged. This blog is essentially a
personal diary now, because I know no one is reading it. I am 100% convinced in
the value of my project. I just wish I had a network of people to connect to it.
If I were still in college I bet this would be easy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 04:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/19/return</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/19/return</guid>
        
        
        <category>annowiki</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fixing a few bugs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;This place is a ghost town.&lt;/span&gt;  But only for now. I am almost
done fixing the minor tweaks before I start inviting beta users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom links are no longer dead. I have set up this blog (obviously) and
created static pages for Terms, Contact, and About on this annowiki.blog. I
don’t see any reason to use anno.wiki to create thouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have created a twitter but haven’t started using it yet. I will be creating a
Mastadon, Facebook, and god knows what else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the indexing system under control. There is one minor tweak I need to
make to annotation edits in the back end (a database adjustment) which will be
the first database migration I will ever do live. I want to do it before I start
inviting people. It will consolidate a lot of gains I made two weeks ago before
I launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also still need to fix the stylistic flubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this will be done in the next week. Then I will invite more users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 05:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/19/update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/19/update</guid>
        
        
        <category>annowiki</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's Alive!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anno.wiki&quot;&gt;anno.wiki&lt;/a&gt; is now live!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;It is currently in beta mode,&lt;/span&gt;  which means registration is only possible with a
magic link I can send out. I will start inviting more people as I get more of
the baubles done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the bottom links, one of which links here, are still mostly dead.
This has to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created the twitter in the course of making this blog, but haven’t done
anything on it yet. Unsure if I want to create a Mastadon and/or a Facebook. I
am more inclined toward Mastadon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gotten the email system working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still indexing lines. Holy cow is that slow. Turns out there’s a bulk_index
function to do what I’m doing but I totally am already ¾ of the way
through indexing so it’s a little late for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still some styling flubs in the pages. Especially for mobile. Verse
gets concatenated the same as everything and, even worse, when everything gets
concatenated on mobile, the paragraph separations disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to set up ssl for the main url, anno.wiki. For now that means secure
connections are only available via &lt;a href=&quot;https://annowiki.herokuapp.com&quot;&gt;annowiki.herokuapp.com&lt;/a&gt;. That won’t be for
long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got &lt;a href=&quot;http://annowiki.blog&quot;&gt;annowiki.blog&lt;/a&gt; to point to /docs in the text-processing repo, but now
I have to try to set that up with this annowikiblog repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this first post is a breathless one. Somewhat of a Mission Accomplished
moment. Because anno.wiki is far from live.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 09:45:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/19/the-beginning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/19/the-beginning</guid>
        
        
        <category>annowiki</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
